i have fallen so far down this rabbit
hole of mlms
it was exactly what was supposed to
happen my friend was supposed to sign up
for the
for doterra i was supposed to sit
through the class
just to comment on this video just to
have this conversation supposed to reach
out to my sister
this something's coming out of this and
it's amazing but i want this video to be
about
sharing the story of what happened with
um
with this woman so i'm going to share my
screen and read it here
i was trying to do it at the perk and it
i can't screen share
so you wouldn't be able to read it too
anyway oh
this is going to get good it's actually
the last part with my sister
all right so uh i don't have my oh i
can't scroll on here okay
i don't need to see me to do this you
can see the screen
okay so this is my response on her video
if you go to my broken math doterra
video i'm responding to this video and
there's a link to it in that description
uh but if you wanted to find it it is
called
it's for essentially for you and it's
called doterra training compensation
plan
and she goes through the power of three
power of three if you get down to seven
then you get thirty two thousand per
month and i went through the video of
like why that's broken
the math that that is a pyramid scheme
in and of itself that there's too much
anyway
so for seven levels are so in order to
do that video i need to ask some
questions
i don't even care about these first few
questions how much money is the person
directly
selling the oils get the person the
first person in your upline gets two
percent but what do you get
that is me why am i okay i'm doing so
awesome with this
oh essentially for you says jubilee
creates something amazing
that's me after i like that i like that
i called myself that but it sounds like
everyone's telling me i create something
amazing
thank you essentially for you after the
person on my front line has been
enrolled 60 days
i get two percent of everything they
order that's not a predatory or problem
at all
that you need them to order in the first
60 days but whatever in the first 60
days i get 20
of everything they order what do you get
for selling them directly to people
she responded jubilee create something
amazing you buy them
for 25 off and sell them for full price
but that's the small picture don't get
hung up there you want to
you want to be earning residual income
do you understand how residual income
works
i did two responses so first one is so
customers who are paying full
price are paying a 55 markup 25
to the seller and 34 to the remaining of
the remaining to the up line
and the sellers have to buy a 150 pv of
wholesale oil a month
so even more like that actually breaks
it more like the fact that
anyway so if you're buying a hundred
dollars essential oil
the person bought it for 75 which is
they actually have to buy 200
oils to get their 150 pv and
all of that money went to the like
whatever this breaks it more
there's 55 markup from that video not a
34 like i talked about
uh and i do understand how residual
income works do you
this is not something that's growing
slash pain while you sleep
this is feeding off the backs of 3 000
people
work and connections and making them
feel bad for not being able to sell an
inferior marked up product
if you do not sell these oils the world
would be better off
not worse off you cannot tell this
business
you cannot sell this business once you
build it
and you cannot walk away stop recruiting
and continue
and continue to make money you can't
walk away and continue to make money
that is you cannot retire
what you have is a pyramid scheme mixed
with a house of cards that makes you
money
until it tumbles down please build a
real business find your purpose i'm sure
you have something amazing to give
humanity
and so do those 3 280 people in the
pyramid to get you to the power of three
level seven
mlms are not in so those are my two
responses and she responded and i
responded this one i responded to
um the second-person response i actually
only read this very first part and i
didn't hit the read more so that's just
fun brain stuff something amazing
i'm very unclear about what you're
saying every single working person
unless they're self-employed is making
money for
someone else that's how all business
works i have a team of almost 1800
people
i love and support them in every way
physically and emotionally
possible i'm pretty confident that not a
single person i work with
would agree with what you've said i
don't feed off the backs of anyone i
lead them by example
doterra is the number one oil company in
the world for a lot of reasons oh this
is gonna get good
i love them because they spend millions
of money a year on science and research
and then they make it available to the
entire industry in hopes of bettering
the quality of all essential oils
i'm not sure what you've heard or why
you would call their products inferior
but it's been shown over and over again
in independent studies
many times the studies were unbeknownst
to dt
that they have a superior product it
sounds like maybe
you've had a bad experience along the
way i'm sorry if that's the case
i responded this is what i responded i
hadn't read it yet
if you are an employee you make a wage
you get paid to work you do not work for
free
the surplus of your labor does go to
someone else and you often have other
benefits such as paid vacation and sick
days and medical insurance
you do not need to get your friends or
family to buy the product or sign up to
work
when you are self-employed you take on
more risk but you get to create your own
vision
often self-employed people make less
than minimum wage while they are
building
and with 9 out of 10 failing it is a big
risk
you have to pay employees market and
price your product to entice customers
but you get to make decisions you get to
create your brand
and hire people that help you fulfill
that vision
now in mlm 99 of people work for
negative funds
they are marketing for doterra in your
case they are using their connections to
get other people to sign up
to also sell the opportunity hence the
pyramid they do not get medical or sick
time or vacation days
all the money goes to their their upline
the seventh lineup in this case of your
video
you do not get to price your product to
compete with other businesses you do not
get to decide on what's in the catalog
you do not get to sell your business to
another person you only get to start
get them to start from scratch selling
them the bs that they too can build what
you have built
duping other people into building it too
you cannot decide
what other people sign up to represent
the same brand you do this is a fake
business
the essential oil even if it's
beneficial do not need to be consumed at
per month you are you are setting the
demand and price for all the customers
and business owners
you have to sell a lifestyle and pretend
you were successful live
ask yourself where the value you create
actually comes from
if it is the essential oil then why does
it need to be at 150 per month
and why the 55 markup so that less
people can afford it
if you were not involved in this if
doterra went under the world would be a
better place
people would get their essential oils
and the amount they needed wanted them
at a cheaper price you were not building
a business you are building a pyramid
that smells really nice
but it is covering up all the bullshit
and then i responded because i hadn't
read the whole thing sorry i did not
fully see your whole comment before
before responding 1800 people working
with you you must have put a lot of time
and money
in to get to that point but for those
eighteen hundred
to get to where you are they have to
each get eighteen hundred for a total of
three million two hundred and forty
thousand
and for those to get to where you are
nearly 6 billion would have to sign up
all buying 150 worth of essential oil
they do not need or want
there is not enough people there is not
enough farmland to grow that much
essential oil
the money in your bank account every
month is from people who are being
coerced into buying a hundred and fifty
dollars worth of product they do not
need at inflated prices
all with the hope that they too can make
money
if they just work hard enough but
there's not enough people
product or land for all of that greed
what's more
people are waking up to the mlm
predatory structure and these will stop
being legal in the next decade
and it will be harder and harder to
recruit as time goes on which we've
already seen
use your money to invest in a real
business and then employ
somebody's home employee in paulie some
of those people who spelled that
those people you already duped
and i haven't really read this fully yet
but uh because i only
i went for a walk the play day i'm gonna
release a video explaining the
beautifulness of my day today
uh but i wanted to go live and share the
reading of these comments jubilee
creates something amazing why did you
stop to comment on my post
really i'm genuinely curious what's
driving you i have so many things i want
to say to clear up the misconceptions
that you are spewing
any of them just one just pick one i'm
spewing let me know
but i do not have the time or desire oh
all of a sudden
however i will say this that one person
has ever been coerced into buying
anything that they don't want or need i
think we've all seen the videos not
necessarily from this moment
people i work with happily buy the
product because it's life-changing they
love it
and they find value in their purchase
every product on earth has a markup
well that's sold into gaming but
whatever
why would you hate doterra because they
have a markup they can either pay
wellness advocates to sit down in
someone's living room and share a
product that they love and understand or
they can pay millions of dollars for
marketing and advertising
to set it on the shelf in a natural food
store i mean if they paid their
people minimum wage to go and sit with
people door-to-door and not sign them up
for a business and that was actually
yeah i'm good with that
where the cashier knows nothing about
the product and couldn't care less
if i had a product that i was passionate
about i would definitely choose the
former that's good business sense
i don't begrudge you tara for making
money any more than i begrudge any other
company that makes money
i'm a big supporter of capitalism well
we differ there
duterte gives away millions of dollars
to projects all over the world
and they are the front line of fighting
human trafficking i'm sure they are
so even if i were overpaying for my oil
i would be happy to do so
as a matter of fact i donate extra money
each month on top of my purchase
to do tara
yay clearly somewhere along the way you
have been hurt by a direct sales company
i would suggest watching the rise dvd by
eric war
oh i will if there's a i i don't take
homework from people but that sounds fun
you can find it on youtube even better i
think it will help you better understand
what's really going on
oh i understand and so but that's not
even the best part is anybody watching
no there are a couple people
hey redemption i'm on like a whole thing
man
so that was i don't did you guys not see
it finally i get it
oh no okay there's my response to the
video i didn't doubt she actually read
that
you can remove my video now so uh i
haven't talked to my sister
in a very long time but we've had one
conversation because of the pandemic i
was like okay
or we didn't discuss anything we've had
a falling out you can watch them
actually redemption can watch them on
periscope because
because that's that's where some of them
are so um i went on this walk on
thursday
whatever we're not getting into that
because that's in the other video how
amazing all the kissmen is that's
that led me to this point but so i
reached out to my
sister because she has an essential oil
company and i wanted to know
i'm about to get in trouble with the
label
where's the mess yes messenger okay
so um on thursday i had sent out a
message to my siblings so because i had
done that
this was open otherwise i probably
wouldn't have texted her asked her
something else but
and she had been talking she'd also been
added she had reached out to me
it worked because of this whole thing
that went down but again i'm releasing
the video later um
have you seen the documentary we're
talking about earth houses what's the
name of the documentary i'll check it
out and i also i have a question about
about her company
my sister's company your loyal your
loyalist
most constant customers that's a thing
right those are words
how much do they buy average per month
i.e
dollar amount i am researching doterra
and then she i think she didn't respond
for all because i was out of cell range
so
she might have responded right away but
i wasn't able to see it
oh doterra is a terrible company
they tried to kill someone i know they
hired her to prove they were sustainable
she pointed out where they were not and
they tried to pay her off
and then put a hit out on her and then
she said atv is about 80
for tp which i don't quite know but it
means you're average being a customer
pays about
80 bucks but we don't have customers
that buy monthly
that my brother said because he's
creating a a thing that is um
about tracking companies that are
ethical and unethical
and and politicians and stuff and it
says now there's something i hadn't
planned to include in the company
tracker and
to assassination attempts so
so then i had the urge to reach out to
my sister to have a conversation we just
got off a two-hour conversation which is
the most healing conversation we've had
the most um interwoven we've we've been
last really probably four or five years
since i started on on my major journey
so that would have been when the kid was
like 18 months old so
six five and a half years i can do basic
math
so this i am like i'm just going to take
a break from dismantling capitalism and
creating game b
and like take down this company because
their essential oils are crap
so then during the conversation with my
sister she had mentioned because she has
a
very high-end essential oil company she
just had to do a lot of this research
and when she works with farmers because
she works with them directly
there's this test called the gcms test
that is certified and and when she was
gonna pay for it it's like 800 bucks per
test
and they throw they and she explained it
but i'm not gonna be able to explain it
um where they can basically tell you if
it's lavender but not if there's other
chemicals in it and stuff and they can't
even really guarantee that they can just
kind of say it is
because they're getting better and
better at faking it if you're not
working directly with the farmers and
the farmers have an incentive to lie
it's not your farm and you have to buy
them from all these different places
then you have to test all of the
different ones
so the fact that do terrorism they don't
own the farms they're not doing that
and um they have this like certification
that's from the company
they own it's their company and so
there's like they're not better than any
other
essential oil company they're just not
um because you can't be there's isn't
the test for it so unless it's a
cooperatively owned farmer you know what
was put on it it's not gonna be the same
thing
the essential oils that they like cure
everything like this woman doesn't get
that like if you
set that you have to spend 150 a month
on them
nobody has to use 150 of essential oil
that's the coercion
and the whole reason she's making money
isn't by selling them like you're
it's it's like like nothing that i just
read was a misconception like if it is
someone comment on mine and tell me
where i'm wrong but like what did i say
that was wrong
yes i know i'm anti-capitalistic and i
have problems with that but i'm not
arguing against all of capitalism in
this it's like
a regular business is okay yours and mlm
is predatory and horrible no matter what
you sell i don't care what you sell it's
horrible
but when you're selling essential oils
then i like
but you're telling people they have to
consume them 150 worth per month in
order to grow a business and you can
grow the business too like i just
explained the math to you great you have
1800 for them to get 1800 you need
a few million people for the few million
people to get 1800
you need six billion people we don't
have enough farmland to consume that
amount of
essential oils we don't like essential
oils are amazing but they're nature
concentrated in a bottle
no one should consume 150 worth like
that's like
instead of eating meat which is already
kind of bad for the environment and i do
it
you like condense a cow into a steak
into like
and then eat it and then condense a cow
into a steak and then eat it instead of
so like every steak you have as a cow
instead of like being able to make
multiple cows it's like even if it's
healthy
essential oils that wasn't bad oh and i
wanted to come on
and read that and share that for
whoever's meant to see it
doterra is a horrible company and i
can't believe my friend got wrapped up
in it like she's someone who's doing
amazing things in the world and
if she anyway so we're gonna have i
reached out to my sister we had this
conversation we were gonna do a
solution raising on essential oils which
is weird because i wouldn't have thought
to do that
but we're gonna talk about with someone
who has a company this essential oil
company
what life currently looks like with
essential oils
what um what's the solution reason again
and then move on to what we would love
it to look like in the perfect future
future and that's where i really don't
have a vision
i don't know we know the research we
know what they actually help with
and everyone has equal access to them
there we go there's my there's that
vision
um and then we're gonna talk about what
10 000 people could do with a hundred
thousand dollars
they actually wanted essential oils
right or access to the
science around essential oils i don't
know what we're going to come up with
but
i had the the feeling that this is
supposed to happen this conversation
with my sister for some reason and
then i invited my friend as well
she may or may not come i'm like there
might that might be the reason maybe the
two of them are supposed to be because
if she's actually passionate about
essential oils and they actually helped
her health
getting involved with my sister's
company might be the thing for her
and she can help move my sister away
from the capitalist model because she's
a resource-based economy person that's
not her sister telling her
and help her see more of the vision
that's coming through my sister
that she was sharing about about these
these earth houses and stuff that she's
feels like she's encountering for the
first time despite the fact i've been
talking about them for decades
whatever she gets you come across the
thing when you come across the thing and
you're open to it ready for it
and i'm ready my brother just because i
don't i don't really know i don't really
am like do you even use essential oils
do you care about them in any way shape
or form you can just come and be
the third sibling and then because the
three of us having one will just be fun
and then if
my friend comes as well there's
something that will come out of it and
then i'm also because my friend
joined doterra this is what my video
will be on youtube the other one i'm so
not watch that one then um see that's
not what i'm supposed to do watch them
all
like them subscribe send them to
everybody all the time um
consume 150 dollars worth of them every
month then sign up for friends to sign
up through friends and sign up for
friends
find you have better things to do with
your time binding
where was i some remind me someone
that's a good thing about live videos
except
for how many years and they're still
they were pretty swatching um finding
rain oh we're gonna have it we're gonna
have thank you but that was it was we're
gonna have a solution raising on
essential oils
and we're gonna have a solution raising
on the uh anti-mlm movement like on what
could we do with ten thousand people and
a hundred thousand dollars
to help bring down the mlm movement help
people coming out of it i don't know
what we're going to create together but
i'm reaching out to the
more of the anti-mlm influencers on
youtube
who um there's something that will come
out of that like there's a reason i'm
involved in that the reason this is
happening
and that is why this youtube channel
exists and i'm also on periscope right
now which is very rare but
when i'm going live publicly i will go
live on both of them
but if you want to watch the journey
unfold you want to catch me on youtube
which is uh
the one that you saw me reading this
whole time jubilee creates something
amazing
by meandering through life because that
is what i'm doing i'm creating a world
that works for everyone
which does mean dismantling capitalism
in my vision but it doesn't mean
forcefully doing it or creating
something that
is is mandatory that people have to be
part of it's about creating things that
are so amazing and voluntary that people
why
why would like the breakdown if you
could be part of an essential oil
company that's a business that's an
actual business and you're gonna make
profit off of it that makes sense if
you're going to
buy from one you need to be able to
trust them
you can probably even trust a i know you
can trust a business or a regular
business even as corrupt and horrible as
they are and i comment on those things
all the time but an mlm is like another
level
of horribleness that you can't trust in
any way and yet the people selling it
are cult-like members
they have like like she can't see any of
the stuff that i'm saying any of the
math that i spew
any of the like what do you mean i duped
people i didn't
really did you tell them they need to
work harder in their business i just
watched your other one all you need to
do is put into
you know 150 a month really 200 a month
and you'll grow this successful business
there aren't enough humans there isn't
enough farmland
no they will not the product is shitty
and you try to murder people
but you know that's cool it's cool just
to prove you're sustainable
that's what they get for hiring a third
party outside for outside
thing oh anyway
we're going to have the solution raising
our essential oils and anti-mlms i
haven't scheduled the one i haven't
had other people say they would be part
of the anti-mlm one but i'm committed
enough that i don't even if i don't get
the influencers on board i'm hosting it
because
the fact that my resource-based economy
friend got involved in one i
can't even imagine she did kind of flip
into toxic fake posit or toxic
positivity over the last few months
where i was like oh those are different
quotes
like oh everything's in your own desire
like your own thoughts and your own
oh i don't you know all the regular
toxic positivity stuff but my sister is
also rather
rather famous for us partly why we had a
falling out
but my sister's come further closer like
we we were
away for so long that somehow it is that
was perfect this is perfect
everything is unfolding in the right
time and if she hadn't joined this emma
like if
she hadn't fallen for this none of this
would be happening
right now including the conversation i
have with my sister so
i will catch you next time